William Oakley

Full Stack Web Developer

Wilmette, IL 60091 (512) 673-0029

wmoakley@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/william-oakley-49b7b618b

GitHub: github.com/woaky1

Portfolio: https://woaky1.github.io/react-portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer and recent graduate from Northwestern's Coding Boot Camp with an extensive background in generating custom educational content for customers in the software industry. Able to see a product from multiple angles and collaborate with both a wide variety of team members and clients. Proven success creating interactive experiences for a variety of Fortune 500 companies as well as local and state governments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript

Technologies: Git, Node.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, HTML, Cascading Style

Sheets, Bootstrap, Express.js

PROJECTS

Chicago School Search

GitHub: github.com/Chicago-School-Information/school-info

Live Website: chicago-school-info.herokuapp.com/

- A website built to help Chicago citizens find data about their local public schools and provide them with contact information for their local alderman.
- Built the Google Map functionality on the page.
- **Tech used includes**: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Google Maps and Google Geocoding APIs, Node.js, Sequelize, Node Express, MySQL

Chicago Commute Checker

GitHub: bit.ly/2rUg5id

Live Website: bit.ly/33QvrC0

- This is a web app where users can choose a CTA line and train stop, then receive
 up-to-date weather and train alerts. The app also recommends whether the user should
 commute or work from home.
- Contributed mainly to the javascript logic.
- Tech used includes: HTML5, CSS3, Materialize, Moment.js, jQuery, Ajax

William Oakley Page 2 of 2

Clicky Game

GitHub: https://github.com/woaky1/clicky_game
Live Website: https://github.com/woaky1/clicky_game/

- A memory game created using React.
- Tech used includes: React, Bootstrap, Node.js

EXPERIENCE

Jellyvision, Chicago, IL - Production Specialist

NOVEMBER 2016 - JULY 2019

- Customized code and content in Jellyvision's ALEX products to meet the specific needs
 of several Fortune 500 companies, universities, and municipal governments.
- Tested for and fixed software bugs.
- Directed voice-over talent.
- Assisted with hiring new talent for the Production Department.

Jellyvision, Chicago, IL - Writer/Director

JULY 2012 - NOVEMBER 2016

- Wrote new interactive conversations for clients as well as scripts for portions of Jellyvision's ALEX line of products.
- Worked with both clients and the creative team to make sure custom conversations satisfied client's needs while staying true to the creative vision.
- Directed voice-over talent for conversations.

CompassLearning, Austin, TX - Lead Writer

JULY 2007 - JUNE 2012

- Wrote engaging multimedia scripts for educational software.
- Worked with animators, software engineers, and education experts to develop characters and story concepts.
- Copyedited ancillary worksheets and quizzes.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University, Chicago, IL - Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Emerson College, Boston, MA - Master of Fine Arts in Creative Writing

Birmingham Southern College, Birmingham, AL - Bachelor of Arts in English

Graduation Honors: Magna Cum Laude and Phi Beta Kappa